# KARIM MAJZOUB

# DATA ANALYST

Paris, France

+33607590680

kmajzoub10@gmail.com

Github Linkedin

# SUMMARY

After 8 years of academia, I discovered a new passion for data analytics. This passion lead me to joining an intensive bootcamp where I had the oppurtunity to work on challenging and stimulating projects. With my new skillset and background in science and engineering, I am ready to take on a role as a Data or Business analyst and derive meaningful insights and actionables from data.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Data analytics projects, Ironhack Paris

Jul 2022 - Sept. 2022

- Walmart retail profit analysis by year, quarter, age and state with Tableau
- Compared healthcare systems between 4 countries using Composite Indicators with SQL
- Predicted whether clients will accept a personal loan from a bank using supervised machine learning
- Analyzed performance of Bundesliga teams between 2017 and 2022 using dashboarding in streamlit and python
- Uber rides clustering classification in the New York area using unsupervised machine learning
- Evaluated the riskiness of an investment using article subtitles by machine learning in python and database creation in SQL
- Winner of the best project in Data analytics among my cohort

## Junior Consultant, Improvalue Paris

Jan. 2022 - Mar. 2022

- Benchmarked client's product against competition by showing strengths and weaknesses of client's product.
- Presented and highlighted findings to client and consultants both in person and online
- Calculated the estimated cycle time and cost to manufacture mechanical parts which led to a 13% decrease in expected cost
- · Worked alongside with senior consultant to analyze and managed KPIs and dashboards in Tableau
- Collaborated with international and local team of 15 people

# Biomedical engineer intern

# Centrale Supelec , Universite de Paris

Feb. 2020 - Jul. 2021

- Analyzed data using python libraries pandas, numpy and scipy.stats
- Created graphs and charts using python libraries matplotlib and seaborn
- Coordinated and managed the progress of the project in a multidisciplinary team of 5 personnel

#### EDUCATION

#### Ironhack Paris,

Jul. 2022-Sep. 2022

### 400+ hours intensive bootcamp

- Programming in Python & SQL, Data collection, management & cleaning, Web scraping. DAX
- Statistics, descriptive and predictive analytics. Data visualization in Seaborn, matplotlib, Tableau
- Machine learning, supervised & unsupervised learning, deep learning, auto machine learning
- Project management (Agile, Scrum, Jira)

### **ENSAM, Mines Paris Tech, University of Paris**

Sept 2019-Sept. 2021

Masters of Science, Biomedical engineering

• Equivalent GPA: 3.5/4

**American University of Beirut** 

Bachelor of engineering, Mechanical engineering

Sept 2016-Juin. 2019

Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

Sept 2013-Juin. 2016

GPA: 3.5/4

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python
MySQL
Tableau
PowerBI
SAS
Microsoft office applications

# LANGUAGES

English (Bilingual)
French (B2-C1)
Arabic (Bilingual)
Dutch (A2)

# EXTRA CIRRUCULAR ACTIVITIES

Basketball
Weighlifting

Podcast host

Music

Travel